Guide to the Yale Objects Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale objects collection
1697-2002
RU 104
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
296.67
(355 boxes)
The collection consists of objects and memorabilia related to Yale including artwork, apparel, silver and porcelain place settings, building hardware, engraving plates, and fraternity insignia.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 45 (YRG 45), Yale objects and memorabilia.
Conditions Governing Access
These objects are available for research.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by object number.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of objects and memorabilia related to Yale including artwork, apparel, silver and porcelain place settings, building hardware, engraving plates, and fraternity insignia.
Collectibles; Souvenirs (Keepsakes); Artifacts (object genre); Yale University -- Collectibles
- Yale objects collection, 1697-2002; Series I
  - #1 Blue and white tea cup with Yale insignia: Blue and white saucer (seems mismatched with cup?), circa 1850-1860 (Box 1)
  - #2 Class of 1896 "Long Distance Cup: Humorous Award Given to Dudley Vaill of Winstead, Conn, at the Class of 1896 Dinner, Yale Club of New York, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - #3 Tile from fireplace of original Dwight Hall: Brown Glazed Brick, 1842-1867 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #4 Part of the bell rope of Yale College broken off in the celebration of Yale's victory over Harvard, 1859 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - #5 Piece of wood from South Middle College, 1750 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - #6 Wooden dagger-shaped item inscribed "Old 'Yale [shell]?', 1859 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - #7 Carved pipe head in the shape of a bulldog, with inlaid eyes, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - #8 Blue and white linen pillowcase; embroidered with a bear wearing a Yale sweater waving a Yale banner on a field hockey stick, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - #9 7 Yale banners, undated (Box 3)
  - #10 Dining ware from a variety of Yale departments, undated (Box 4)
  - #11 Cross-section of Old Yale Fence. Mounted on wood and framed, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - #12 Wood plaque with metal, mirror, and painted Yale emblem, engraved "Presented to Steven Napier Pawling"; Support piece, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - #13 Cross-section of the Old Yale Fence, with pen drawing of the Fence, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - #14 Cross-section of the Old Yale Fence; Painted: men sitting on the Fence, fans, and fraternity emblem, circa 1879-1880 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - #15 White pennant with blue "Y", undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - #16 Wood Gavel, painted black, with metal band engraved: "Presented to James Francis O'Connor by the Yale Kent Club... ", 1909 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - #17 Yale Athletic Plaque, wood and metal, with Yale Bulldog, banner, oars, and football; inscribed with cheers, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - #18 Collection of Yale Emblems (two framed collections; 3 loose emblems), undated (Box 6, Folder 2A-B)
  - #19 Bronze Bas-Relief; portrait medallion; "Charles Upson Clark, Searcher After Truth.. .", 1949 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - #20 Gordon Brown Memorial Prize; metal; nude figure and Yale emblem, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - #21 Sheffield School of Science headband, Class of 1909, white felt numbers '09 S on blue felt, with elastic string (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - #22 Engraving plate attached to block of wood; contains motto "Progress in Industry." View of Mason Laboratory, circa 1948 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - #23 Copper engraving plate, attached to block of wood. View of unidentified building, circa 1948 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - #24 Copper engraving plate, attached to block of wood; View of Mason Laboratory, circa 1948 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - #25 Engraving plate, view of singing on the "Old Campus" during World War II. Attached to wooden block, circa 1940-1944 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - #26 2 Metal engraving plates. Yale letters, classes of 1870 and 1871, 1870-1871 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - #27 Engraving plate of [zodiac signs]?, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - #28 Copper engraving plate of Dr. Theodore Thorton Munger in cap and gown, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - #29 Yale 1907 Banner; white felt on blue felt (Box 7)
  - #30 Alpha Delta Phi Fraternity Plaque; wood painted black with metal; with emblem and date, [1832]? (Box 8)
  - #31 2 metal dies for the Deforest Senior Mathematical prize. One die contains lettering and a Yale emblem, the other a floral motif, 1855 (Box 9)
  - #32 Engraving plate of photograph of Yale Class of 1893 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - #33 Steel engraving plate, view of Old Yale College Library (now Dwight Chapel), undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - #34 Steel engraving plate, view of archway in the Memorial Quadrangle of Yale Campus, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - #35 Steel engraving plate, view of archway in the Memorial Quadrangle of Yale Campus, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - #36 Steel engraving plate, view of Harkness Quadrangle, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - #37 The electrotype plate for song "The Khaki and the Blue." (song sheet included), 1918 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - #38 Brass engraving plate for class of 1858 album; S.V. Hunt's view of Yale College (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - #39 Copper engraving plate of invitation to dedication of Dwight Hall, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - #40 Copper engraving plate of the insignia of Kappa Sigma Epsilon, 1840 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - #41 Copper Engraving plate: invitation to Junior Exhibition, 1838 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - #42 Wood and metal engraving plate; diagram of main floor of a Yale College, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - #43 Engraving plate of Yale College reunion [1920s]?, circa 1950 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - #44 Electrotype plates used for J.M. Whiton's pamphlet, "The First Intercollegiate Regatta" (Harvard-Yale Regatta of 1852), undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - #45 Electrotype plates used for J.M. Whiton's pamphlet, "The First Intercollegiate Regatta" (Harvard-Yale Regatta of 1852), undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - #46 Plate for photographic plate of Ingalls Rink; Metal and wood, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - #47 A view of the buildings of Yale College in New Haven, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - #48 Plate for photograph of Mason Laboratory, metal and wood, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - #49 unidentified [possibly early Yale College buildings], undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - #50 Plate for title page of Bishop Berkeley's "Theory of Vision"; Copper and wood, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - #51 Plate for title page of Bishop Berkeley's "Theory of Vision"; Copper and wood, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - #52 Engraving plate of Phi Beta Kappa insignia, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - #53 Plate for title page of Bishop Berkeley's "Theory of Vision"; Copper and wood, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - #54 Plate for diagram of steel framing for unidentified Yale building; Metal and wood, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - #55 Plate for diagram of steel framing for unidentified Yale building; Metal and wood, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - #56 Plate for diagram of steel framing for unidentified Yale building; Metal and wood, undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - #57 Plate for diagram of steel framing for unidentified Yale building; Metal and wood, undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - #58 Plate for diagram of steel framing for unidentified Yale building; Metal and wood, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - #59 Plate for diagram of steel framing for unidentified Yale building; Metal and wood, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - #60 Delta Kappa Epsilon fraternity plaque; wood and metal, undated (Box 12)
  - #61 Sugar bowls: 3 larger flowered ones and 3 smaller ones with blue, undated (Box 13)
  - #62 Plaster Portrait medallion of David Ely Bartlett (Y. 1828) made by one of his deaf-mute Chinese students, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - #63 Wooden snuff box containing slips with names of students of class of 1863; with genre scene and leaf design, circa 1860-63 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - #64 Letter opener, wood, in the shape of a saber. "1687" carved into it. From the mantelpiece in the study of Rev. Samuel Russell of Branford, Connecticut, circa 1697 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - #65 Wooden Coffin, "Yale Carved." On paper: "In Memoriam... " Souvenir of Burial of Euclid, November, 1858---by the Class of 1851 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - #66 Ivory pencil. At one end one can look through a small hole and see a view of old Dwight Hall, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - #67 Silver matchbox favor inscribed: "Senior German Yale '96", 1896 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - #67.1 Metal die of the Yale family seal in a round wooden box, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - #68 Silver dance favor (favor at the sophomore German). Inscribed: "Yale '96 Jan 29th 1894." Hanging from a small leather strap, circa 1894-1896 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - #69 Metal belt buckle, octagonal, with Yale seal in center, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - #70 Class of 1932 Ring of Pryce H. Evans (d. 1976), Milwaukee artist; gold plated, blue stone (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - #71 Quill pen presented to Mr. Keogh on the occasion of a speech delivered in the Yale Club of New York. Blue feather. Glass ink-stand painted blue. Pebbles, 1927 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - #72 Yale University plaque; coat of arms; laminated wood, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - #73 Framed color print of Yale hockey player with Yale insignia; issued by Murad Cigarettes, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - #74 Rev. Ezra Stiles' baptismal cap and dress; cotton and lace edging, 1727 (Box 14A)
  - #75 Jackson Ware bowl depicting Yale and the State House; floral pattern, black on white; "Jackson's Warranted" mark, circa early 1800s (Box 15)
  - #76 Jackson Ware bowl depicting Yale and the State House; floral pattern, black on white; "Jackson's Warranted" mark, circa early 1800s (Box 15)
  - #77 Jackson Ware bowl depicting Yale and the State House; floral pattern, black on white; "Jackson's Warranted" mark, circa early 1800s (Box 15)
  - #78 Cross Campus Library T-shirt, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - #79 Yale Bicentennial Cup, with Yale buildings in relief. Pewter. Marked "The Ed. Malley Co, New Haven"; made in Germany, 1901 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - #80 Wooden paddle of Yale fraternity Psi Upsilon. Decorative carving and lettering, 1909 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - #81 Silver plated trowel used at laying of the cornerstone of the memorial buildings: cornerstone of Woolsey Hall, University Hall, and the Memorial Vestibule, 1901 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - #82 Emblem of the Lost Digamma, 1897-1898 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - #83 Pottery porridge bowl, light blue and white. View of Yale campus and the New Haven Green with floral border. Made in New Haven, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - #84 Blue Wedgwood plate. View of Yale College and old Yale fence with floral border, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - #85 Jackson Ware vegetable bowl; brown and white view of New Haven Green with floral border. Made in New Haven, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - #86 Jackson Ware soup bowl, depicting Yale College and State House; floral pattern; brown on white, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - #87 Blue and white platter, view of New Haven Statehouse, with floral border. Made in New Haven, undated (Box 18)
  - #88 Set of 5 Wedgwood plates; new series designed by Robert Galvin. Depict various Yale buildings, 1949 (Box 19)
  - #89 Blue Staffordshire serving plate, views of Yale buildings. Edward Malley & Co, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - #90 Souvenir plate of New Haven, depicting Yale buildings, made in England; blue on white, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - #91 Plate with view of old Osborn Hall, in color with blue decorative border. Made in Germany, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - #92 Hat and stole from Universite de Lyon, yellow and black; stole from Universite de Paris, white, red, and blue, 1950 (Box 21)
  - #93 Light blue cap and gown, used by Abel S. Clark, presumably at the Bicentennial, 1867 (Box 21)
  - #94 Light blue and white mortarboard with white tassel, 1871 (Box 21)
  - #95 Set of 12 Wedgwood Yale plates with a duplicate of Old Chapel plate, 1931 (Box 22)
  - #96 Miniature wooden model of Old Brick Row (seven buildings), undated (Box 23, Folder 1A-F)
  - #97 Wooden-handled toothbrush, natural bristles; brush end painted white, [1800s]? (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - #98 Blue silk flag with white felt "YALE" letters, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - #99 Brown glass brandy bottle, 1823 (Box 24)
  - #100 12 dinner plates, Syracuse china, undated (Box 25)
  - #101 Painted ceramic model of Yale Bowl; Lenox Mark; Inscribed on bottom: F.J. Cuthbertson succcessor to A.F. Wylie, New Haven (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - #102 Rose ornament from Battell Chapel Organ, wood painted with tempera, removed 1951 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - #103 Glass paperweight with photograph of Rev. Timothy Dwight, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - #104 Piece of one of the Elm trees cut down to give place for the Recitation Building at Yale College, New Haven, 1791 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - #105 Silver castor sugar shaker with filigree top, 1701 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - #106 Ceramic ashtray with shape of a top hat. Brown glazing with incised design of "dancing graduates", made by F.M. Wilson (Y. 1894) (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - #107 Gavel made from the corner post of the old Yale Fence, corner of Chapel and College Streets. Cedar. Made by George A. Treak, 1888 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - #108 Wooden gavel, undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - #109 Yale Student Council Official Ballot Box, wood, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - #110 '91 consolidated football team mug, ceramic with brown glaze, inscribed with names of players, 1891 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - #111 Wooden box with picture of Yale College pasted on the lid, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - #112 Wooden bookend with Yale emblem embossed on leather, undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - #113 Brick marked "Old South Yale--1893" (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - #114 Wooden Mallet, undated (Box 27A, Folder 1)
  - #115 Piece of the Yale Fence taken by classes of 1890 and 1891 (Box 27A, Folder 2)
  - #116 Wooden drumstick of Old College drum, undated (Box 27A, Folder 3)
  - #117 Small wooden bat with blue ribbon, undated (Box 27A, Folder 4)
  - #118 Piece of silk made from Ezra Stiles' cocoons (said to be the silk used for the wedding dress of Mrs. Stiles); gold with leaf design, undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - #119 Tile decorated with the emblem of He Boule, Yale fraternity, 1943 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - #120 A pitch pipe or wooden whistle presented by Class of 1826 to John G. Adams, 1820 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - #121 Sterling silver matchbox, inscribed "Yale '92" (favor at senior or junior promenade), 1892 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - #122 Paperweight presented by Timothy Dwight College to the 5 or 6 students who have done the most for the college in a given year; metal with TD insignia, 1942 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - #123 Book made from stone of Wrexham Church now fitted into Wrexham tower, Branford/Saybrook colleges (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - #124 Pane from a window of the"Gold Coast" of the Memorial Quadrangle (later Saybrook dining room); "Yale" intertwined with quill pen marked "Yale Courant", 1953 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - #125 Silk pennant, white "Y" on blue; rolled in a cylidrical case which also functions as the staff, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - #126 Ruth Stiles' needlebook, pink and green silk, metal clasp engraved "RS" and "1792" (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - #127 Metal plate with Greek letters Phi Gamma Delta (Yale chapter called Nu Deuteron, chartered 2/22/1875), undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - #128 Copper/Brass bicentennial pen knife, 1901 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - #129 Medal from the Universite de Lyon, presented to President Seymour, 1946, designed by Muller, undated (Box 28A, Folder 1)
  - #130 Medal presented by the Universite de Braxelles to President Seymour; designed by G. de Ureese. In case, undated (Box 28A, Folder 2)
  - #131 China demi-tasse cup with picture of Osborne Hall, New Haven, Connecticut, undated (Box 28A, Folder 3)
  - #132 Ten pieces of silver, one from each of the college dining halls, undated (Box 29, Folder 1A-I)
  - #133 Collection of nine plaques with Yale colleges coats of arms; laminated wood, undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - #134 Three copper plates for the old library bookplates, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - #135 Hitchcock Chair (not original) with a picture supposedly representing Saybrook Point and the collegiate school there, circa 1800s
    General note
    see archivist for location
  - #135.1 Collection of four pewter drinking steins for Yale Fraternities, circa 1908-1929 (Box 30)
  - #136 American flag draped over the casket of W.H. Taft, 1930 March 11 (Box 31)
  - #137 Chamber pot used by Franklin D. Roosevelt at the time when he was presented with his honorary degree, 1934 (Box 32)
  - #138 Metal tray made from the plate of the invitation to President Hadley's inauguration; inscribed in reverse," The President and Fellows of... ", circa 1899-1900 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - #139 Window pane with interlocking triangles with "Yale" and "Alta Elens", undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - #140 Metal Psi Upsilon plaque, undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - #141 Woodblock of Elihu Yale used on the covers of the Yale Literary Magazine (first used in 1836) in case, made by Tuttle, Morehouse, and Taylor (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - #142 Secession Flag, Alumni Hall, 1861 put up by Southern students of Yale (possibly taken down by Roswell Parish Y. 1864); homemade (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - #143 Yale banner, white on blue background, undated (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - #144 Yale Class of 1865 flag; white on blue (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - #145 Dishes from the Fence Club Grill, undated (Box 34)
  - #146 Blue ceramic ashtray, "Lux et Veritas.", undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - #147 Spoon from Moseley's New Haven House, undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - #148 Souvenir baseball bat from game between Amherst and Yale, carved from a real bat used in the game, 1879 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - #149 Yale '83 banner, white on blue; with blue hat ribbon (worn in 50th year reunion), 1883 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - #150 A piece of the Yale Fence, undated (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - #151 Fragment from a dish broken in the Common Riot, 1923 March 12 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - #152 Sterling silver trowel used in laying cornerstone of Sterling Law buildings, 193o June 14 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - #153 China cup [from Yale Yacht Club?] made by Sterling China, undated (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - #154 Eight pieces of door hardware from a student room at Yale, undated (Box 35A, Folder 1)
  - #155 Yale pennant in a wooden cylinder which also functions as the staff, undated (Box 35A, Folder 2)
  - #156 Wolf's Head insignia, metal, undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - #157 Slate writing tablet in 2 hinged sections, undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - #158 Wooden Phi Beta Kappa Key carved by Leander Elmer Wakefield (Y. 1842) to hang on the wall of his room; in case, undated (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - #159 Piece of the Yale Fence, undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - #160 Trowel used at the laying of the cornerstone of Yale Divinity School; made in England, undated (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - #161 Trowel used at the laying of the cornerstone of Battel Chapel, 25 June 1874 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - #162 Pewter stein with fraternity insignia Zeta Psi. "Edwin Armstrong Sweet 1932" (Box 36A, Folder 7)
  - #163 Pewter stein won by 1906 Sheffield Scientific School in race with 1907 Yale College, October 24, 1903 (Box 36A, Folder 8)
  - #164 Ceramic mug with blue glazing, ornamented in gold with the Yale seal, 1896 (Box 36A, Folder 9)
  - #165 Ceramic mug with fraternity insignia and the date April 19, 1911 (of the type used at Temple Bar, Temple and Center Streets (Box 36A, Folder 10)
  - #166 Class of 1895 ceramic mug, molded design of Yale men and cheers; "BBL", "R.H.B.", "March 2 1895" inscribed on bottom (Box 36A, Folder 11)
  - #167 Brown glazed ceramic Toby jug, undated (Box 36A, Folder 12)
  - #168 Painted ceramic ashtray with figure of the Yale bulldog wearing '96 shirt, 1896 (Box 36A, Folder 13)
  - #169 Doctoral hoods of George Park Fisher (L.L.D. Yale and D.D. Edinborough), undated (Box 37)
  - #170 Reunion banner for the class of 1883 with "Yale '83" in white on blue felt (Box 37)
  - #171 White glazed ceramic pot with Yale insignia; awarded for Yale Coffee, first grand prize St. Louis World's Fair, 1904 (Box 38)
  - #172 Set of 12 glasses, each with the arms of a residential college, in color (Box 39)
  - #173 Trowel used at the laying of the cornerstone of Sterling Memorial Library. Made at Tiffany & Co, 1928 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - #174 Hunting Knife of George Borup, class of 1907, used by him on the Perry Expedition to the North Pole, 1908. (Broken spring). Ivory and metal, circa 1908 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - #175 China plate, blue with Yale seals and pink roses (has been mended), undated (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - #176 Sterling Silver spoon with view of Durfee Hall engraved on bowl of spoon and profile of A.T. Hadley on handle (in porcelain, in color), undated (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - #177 Sterling Silver spoon view of Osborn Hall. With decorative motif and name "Lottie" engraved, circa 1901 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - #178 Blue and white china plate, with Yale seal and crossed "Y" pennants (has been mended). Embossed, undated (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - #179 China plate, view of old Osborn Hall in color, with Rose border and gold edged, undated (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - #180 Wooden piece of the Yale College clock hand, broken off at 12:15 AM, December 14, 1861, circa mid 1800s (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - #181 Blue felt beanie with white lettering: "Yale", undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - #182 Wooden gavel, belonged to Rev. Gardiner Spring Plumley, D.D, who organized the Yale Alumni Association of Fairfeild County, CT, undated (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - #183 Wooden pipe with ivory bulldog bowl. Red satin ribbon wrapped around, undated (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - #184 Note of City Bank of New Haven to Yale Fraternity, Alpha Delta Phi. Framed, 1914 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - #185 Three cotton armbands, worn by Yale wardens in World War II. Khaki colored, circa 1944-1945 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - #186 Fragment of Jeffersonian Flag, red linen, 1880 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - #187 Drawing instruments of Henry L. Rowland, class of 1894s. Various metal implements: magnet, tweezer, etc. In leather box with purple velvet lining, undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - #188 Brown Belt with "Thulia '62" printed on it, circa 1862 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - #189 Wooden Fraternity paddle to Frank Whittemore from Bill Goodrich, Alpha Sigma Theta, with decorative carvings, 10943 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - #190 Wooden piece of bannister of Old South College, undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - #191 Class Day pipe of the Sheffield Scientific School. Clay, with decorative carving "S. 1900" in relief (Box 42)
  - #192 Wooden Fraternity Paddle of Zeta Psi, carved "To Scovill Aspinwell from George Riggs" with seal engraved, 1928 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - #193 Unidentified scroll in Chinese or Japanese lettering, undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - #194 Blue and white silk scarf with lettering "Yale '78 Quarter Centennary", 1878 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - #195 Blue crockery mug with metal Yale seal. Class of 1897 (Box 42)
  - #196 White linen shirt of Ezra Stiles, circa mid 1900s (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - #197 Metal belt buckle showing a black and white photograph of Osborn Hall, undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - #198 and #198a Green metal and wood fountain pen used by President Wm. H. Taft when signing a bill and photograph of taft with pen, 1911 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - #199 Gold plated Paper Cutter, incribed "Yale Bicentennial 1701-1901 New Haven." With Yale Seal and decorative handle with owl on it (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - #200 Metal section of a "John Brown" railroad rail. Used to support the vault in old Sheffield Hall. Roughly hourglass shaped, undated (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - #201 Metal Harness crest, depicting a wild boar within a net, with an acorn in its mouth, undated (Box 43, Folder 1)